So, in the previous topic, we have seen
the internal
of Kafka producer.
Now, let's today
start with the setup. We will set up the
producer.
Okay. So, let's start without wasting
any time. The first and the foremost is
the dependency. What dependency we need?
So, this is the only dependency we have
to add that is
org.springframework.kafka.spring-kafka.
This is the only dependency.
So, this dependency pulls
all the spring wrapper layer, which are
built on top of Kafka client dependency.
So, you get Kafka client dependency. You
can say that the implementation. And
this is the abstraction layer.
Okay?
>> [clears throat]
>> So,
spring wrapper layer
is you can say that mostly an
abstraction.
So, like Kafka template, which is
required to send message. So, you or any
developer who is working with Kafka,
right, producer, they will deal with
mostly this layer.
And internally, this spring wrapper
layer make use of Kafka client
dependency. So, like Kafka template, we
will going to use it to send message.
Kafka admin, like it is it is required
to manage the topic.
So,
once dependency added,
in a step two, what we will do is add
the bootstrap brokers. If you remember
from the previous topic, I told you that
setting up the producer is just like a
one line of code. If you have to send a
message from producer
to broker,
all you have to just do is Kafka
template. dot send.
And provide the topic name, key, and the
your message object.
All we have to do in the configuration,
all we have to provide is this.
Kafka bootstrap servers. Okay, so these
are both the brokers.
So, you remember from our cluster setup,
we have two brokers, broker one and
broker two.
Okay, so both the
broker address I have added here.
So, this is required. So, why it's
called bootstrap server is
say initially when the first time you
are starting the producer.
Producer do does not know
like, okay, for this topic A partition
zero, which one is the leader? Which
broker is leader?
For topic A partition one, which broker
is leader? I don't know. Producer don't
know. Okay. So, the bootstrap server
major is that
you can say that and the first time we
are
starting the producer, it will invoke
any one of it.
It will invoke any one of the broker and
ask that, "Hey, can you provide me the
metadata information?"
Now, broker
generally broker also have metadata
information cache, but let's say if they
don't have, it will goes to the active
controller,
fetch the metadata,
and then return to the producer.
And producer also cached it.
Now, from the next call, it doesn't need
this bootstrap server. It just check the
metadata information which this producer
has. Okay.
For topic A partition zero, it will
check its metadata, who is the broker,
it will directly invoke it. The address
information would be present into that
metadata information.
So, that's why it's named bootstrap.
Only the first time.
>> [clears throat]
>> Uh only the first time producer needs
it. After that, it maintain the
this metadata information cache.
Now, the question might come is that,
"Okay,
this metadata information which producer
stores, how frequently does it refresh?"
So, see this one.
So, we can configure that.
>> [clears throat and cough]
>> Sorry.
Sorry for this. So, we can configure
this. spring.kafka.producer.properties
metadata.max.age.milliseconds.
Okay, so currently I have configured 5
minutes. So, after 5 minutes,
this producer will update this metadata
information. It will ask broker again,
"Give me the latest metadata
information."
Okay? So, you can change it you want,
and even if you don't write it,
default is 5 minutes only.
Okay?
So, that's why I mentioned specifically
for producer
to run.
All you need is this one
application.properties.
Bootstrap server.
After that, you can just simply do
kafkaTemplate.send,
and you are able to send a
message to the broker.
Okay. Now, step three, what we are
doing? We are going to add a topic. So,
if you remember from the cluster setup,
we created a topic using the shell
script.
But, we can also create through our
producer. So, whenever producer
application will start up,
we can have
we can create a bean
where during a startup it will check,
"Hey, this
topic exist or not?" If not, it will
create a new topic for us.
So, I have created
one class, Kafka producer config and
annotated with @configuration
and this I'm adding one bean.
Okay? So, the name you can give
anything. Order events topic. I have
given order events topic. And what
type of bean it return new topic. This
is we have to return.
And there is a builder topic builder
which is present. We can use it to
create a topic. Topic builder
.name What is the name of the topic you
want to give? Topic builder .name
topic name .build.
So, when your application will start, it
will check, "Hey, does
in the cluster order events topic is
present or not?" If not, this topic will
get created.
>> [snorts]
>> Now, you might be thinking that, "Hey,
this is very very simple, right? Only
like we have to give the
topic name."
So,
just recall it.
When we set up a controller
and broker
we in there
.property files, we have
added so many
default.
Like in controller properties, if you
remember the config properties, we set
up how many partition.
Okay? And uh how what is the replication
factor?
What is the replication factor? We have
already provided there in the
controller.properties.
And in the broker
we have
defined the
default like segment size.
Segment size.
And also the cleanup strategy.
So, that's why if you just only provide
the name
all these default would be picked from
the respective
property files.
>> [snorts]
>> But
Spring Boot also provide us a way to
override these defaults.
Okay. So, here the same way
this is just another example, same
example but with the
configuration I am showing you
that
Sorry.
topicbuilder.name
the topic name here you can provide any
topic name.
Now, dot partition. So, it's a builder.
You can builder in low-level design you
might have seen the builder design
pattern. So, it's just following the
builder design pattern at last it will
doing build.
So, dot partition. So, here we will give
the partition number. Now, here if you
see that controller.properties
Okay. So, there we have already defined
the default. If you don't add it here
it will be picked from here. Controller
1.properties, controller2.properties we
have already provided the default.
Replicas we have already provided, but
we can override it.
Similarly, the config
topicconfig.retention.milliseconds.config.
So, if you don't provide it it will be
picked from the broker. So, if you see
remember from the broker
we have
we can have like log.retention.hours
168 7 7 days, right? So, here
in the millisecond I've just provided
the same
7 days.
For how long
the logs would be retained.
>> [snorts]
>> topicconfig.cleanup.policy.config
whether you want
uh delete or compress
minimum in-sync replica how many uh ISR
minimum
in-sync replica we have already uh seen
in the cluster like
so that we can divide provide into the
broker dot properties file but we can
also override here similarly segment
byte size
like here we have given right log dot
segment dot bytes 1GB the similarly you
can provide it here also override it
here.
>> [snorts]
>> So the
whether you just provide a name topic
name or you can provide all the default
set in the config properties
or you can even during the topic
creation you can provide all the
configuration like this too both are
fine.
Okay
now during application startup it will
check if a specific topic exist or not
if not it will create the topic request.
Okay let's see that.
Let's see that so here
>> [clears throat]
>> So
I have in the configuration
class
order events this is the topic name
which I have to create partition I am
creating for replica two
and all other information I have kept
the same
but let's set up the cluster one and let
me first remove everything like first
remove everything like broker one dot
logs gone
broker two dot logs gone.
Similarly controller one
one dot logs gone
controller two dot logs gone so all four
you can say that our servers in a
cluster is gone
now what we have to do is that
first create a cluster ID.
We first need a cluster ID.
So, this is our new cluster ID. And now
we will create controller and broker and
attach it with this cluster.
>> [snorts]
>> So, just copied it.
And just replacing
this new cluster ID. First I'm creating
controller one.
Then controller two
with the same cluster ID.
Then broker one.
And then broker two.
So, now in a one cluster, I have now two
controller and two broker.
Okay? Now, let's just start the
controller one first.
So, yeah, controller one.
And here I will start the controller
two.
Okay?
So, both controller started.
Both controller started? Yes.
Now, let me start the broker.
Broker one.
We'll start broker two.
So, both broker are also started.
Let's see the status
for order \hyphen} events topic.
Currently this event this topic does not
exist at all. Now, let me start the
server. So, here if you see, I have this
bean only bean at the rate configuration
to create an order \hyphen} events.
So now let's start the server.
Server is started. Now let's again
check describe
topic order hyphen events.
Partition 0 1 2 3. So total four
partition and two replicas.
That's what we have defined here.
Four partition, two replicas.
So
we have set up we have created the topic
through a Spring Boot itself. Okay? And
all the library which we required is
this.
Because this internally brings the Kafka
admin
which is
used to manage the topic.
Now once the topic is created, we have
to send the event. Now there is a work
of Kafka template.
>> [snorts]
>> Send events.
So let's see the use case one. So if you
have followed the previous video,
you know that when we
do send,
what are the stages? First is
serializer.
Second is partitioner.
Third is
record accumulator.
Then compression.
Then sender thread.
Okay?
Generally, we don't need any
configuration. Like all the
configuration we want is this.
The bootstrap server. That's the only
one.
Okay?
But since we have already know the
internals of producer,
we can configure this all five steps
also.
So this is the use case one. This is
what we wanted.
Sorry. [snorts]
So in the serializer step,
we know that
it serialize two thing, key and value.
So, the key I wanted to serialize as a
string
and value JSON.
Okay? So, means uh my value or the
object which ultimately go as a event is
the POJO class. So,
it gets serialized with JSON. JSON
serializer.
Then in the partition,
we have to use send with key. So, I'm
just telling you the use case which we
have to implement. So, we have to test
with send with key
so that the related event goes to the
same partition.
If the key is same, it should always
pick the same partition.
Then in the record accumulator, what we
can configure is the batch size, the
linger,
overall buffer. Overall buffer for the
batches. So, you know that we can create
many batches. Now, each batch size we
have
uh specify, maximum they can have is 32
KB.
But, overall size we also have to limit,
right? We can't have like so many
batches. Okay? So, the maximum size is
32 MB.
Okay? So, what does it mean? When the 32
MB is reached, the means you have
created so many batches
that over the whole buffer which is kept
for the batches,
32 MB is full.
Now, what would happen is if you try to
do send,
you won't be able to do further.
Because when you try to do send more,
means you are trying to add more
information into existing batch or you
are trying to create a new batch. So,
this send will get blocked.
Hey, wait.
Memory is full.
And how much time it should wait?
We should also configure that. Let's say
60 second is the time we are telling
that wait for 60 second.
If after 60 second also this there is no
space freedom then
fail.
Okay?
So, this is the record accumulator we
have to set up.
Compression we will use any one of them
snappy gzip or there are so many. So,
yes we will not just go with
uncompressed.
We will compress it.
And in the center thread
in flight we have to use five and the
retry three.
So,
this is our requirement.
Now, if you see that it's very very
simple. First is I have just set up a
controller.
Just exposed an end end point so that
the control reaches to our application.
So, \slash} API \slash} order \slash}
with key. So, this method will get
invoked.
What this is doing is simply invoking
the producer service send with key.
Nothing much. Okay, it's just invoking
the service.
So, this controller no nothing special.
>> [snorts]
>> Now, in this service
the first thing is auto wiring.
Kafka template the key and the value
data type.
So, key is a string.
And the value I have a order pojo. So,
this is a pojo class I have created.
Getter and setter.
So, that I have added.
Okay?
And for
you know that
for key I have this is our requirement,
right? For key is a string.
And the value is JSON. So, we for the
JSON you know that we need an object.
So, that's why value I have taken as an
object. Order object pojo.
And just provide the name.
And who will do this auto wiring?
A spring boot will automatically resolve
this dependency.
Okay? Uh when it find this, right?
When you add this dependency.
It will automatically add Kafka template
dependency and it automatically
auto wire it.
Okay?
>> [snorts]
>> Now, this is the method which ultimately
our controller is calling, send with
key.
And this is the
you can say that uh the object which we
have.
So, I'm taking out the key. With key we
have to send, right? So, order ID I'm
taking as a key.
Now, this is the only line which is
required to send an event to a broker.
Kafka template
\dot} send
the topic we can Currently, I have
hardcoded it here. We can also put into
application.properties and read from
there.
So, topic name
key
and the value.
>> [snorts]
>> That's all.
And you remember
that your application thread
work is still
when you do send, work is still
record accumulator only.
Once uh so it what it will do
uh
So, here it will do serializer, then
partitioner, and after that record
accumulator. After that your application
thread
just return.
Okay? So, we This returns the future
object.
Record metadata, if you remember. From
the previous video.
Okay? All we have to do is that handle
the callback.
So, now here I'm just handling the
callback.
Whatever the future object it will
return future \dot} when complete
Now, when
whenever the sender thread
send the response
right?
This will get complete when complete.
And I'm just checking here. So, here we
have a result or exception. If exception
equals to null, means it is success. And
if you remember
that if you go inside this Kafka
template.send
What is the future? It will send off
record metadata. And in record metadata
has information about partition. This
event is stored in which partition?
And what's the offset number? So, I'm
just printing it here.
But if there is an exception, what
exception I got? This is normal Java. We
have already seen in the Java series
completable future part.
Okay? How to handle the callbacks?
But only the point here is that
I have added a controller. Controller
does nothing, just pass the request to
the service. In service, I have
autowired the Kafka template. Whatever
the key and the value, I have just
provided here.
Now, using this Kafka template object,
I'm invoking the send. Provide the topic
name, the key, and the value. And I got
a future object.
If you have to handle the callback, you
can handle it. Like it's depend upon
company to company, their application to
application, how you want to handle the
callback.
Okay, this is just a POJO class.
And now
all the work is there in two
application.properties.
So, this producer is running on this
port. This is the name of my producer
application.
This is the only required config
bootstrap server. I have already told
you initially.
So, all the both the brokers which are
running on this port I have added here.
Now
Also, I have discussed there that okay,
it load the metadata
and how
frequently we have to refresh it. So, by
default is 5 minutes, so I don't have to
write it, but just for clarity that yes,
this thing exist.
I have added that refresh it the
metadata after 5 minutes.
And if you remember from the
architecture video, in-sync replicas,
you can provide all
0 1 and all like
0 means only leader.
Like 0 means like don't even wait, fire
and forget.
Fire and forget.
One is like only leader should be able
to successfully receive the event.
And all means that So, we are giving
instruction
to the broker that
once the event is published, make sure
that all if if it is all, all the
replicas which are present into ISR list
also
get the update.
Only after that
send me the acknowledge that yes, done.
Broker work is done.
We have already seen that.
Now, let's comes to our
requirement serializer.
You know that the step one is
serializing in which we have to
serialize the key and the value.
So, spring.kafk.producer
key serializer.
I already told you in the previous that
we have so many inbuilt serializer. We
don't have to write.
So,
a string serializer I'm using.
For value,
value hyphen serializer, I'm using JSON
serializer because our
object is POJO and JSON serializer can
work with the POJOs objects.
Okay, so serializer done.
In the record,
partitioner,
what we have the requirement is that
send with key. That's what we are doing
it. We are sending it with the key.
Okay?
Now, record accumulator
the first is that the linger. Linger
should be 20 ms, so we have defined
here.
spring.kafka.producer.properties.linger.ms
Okay? So, maximum producer will wait for
20 ms to fill up the batch. After that,
it will
close the batch
and make it ready to send to the broker.
Each batch size. So, this is I'm setting
the batch size that 32 KB.
Okay? And overall buffer for the
batches, overall. Okay? So,
spring.kafka.producer.properties.buffer.memory.
buffer.memory. So, I have provided 32
MB.
Okay?
So, once this is full
if you any further invoke the send, it
will get blocked.
Okay?
So, till what time it will get blocked?
This.
spring.kafka.producer.properties.max.block.ms.
Just initial.
Then the This is the config.
max.block.ms.
60 second, it will get blocked.
If in 60 second
there is no space in the buffer
Okay?
After 60 second, the request will
immediately fail.
No space.
Okay?
So, see all configuration we have set
for the record accumulator.
Compression and we have to use one of
it. So, yeah, compression.
So, this is just an initial. This is the
config.compression.type.
I am using Snappy.
Sender thread retry.
spring.kafka.producer.retries.
We have to do three. So, internally
whenever the sender thread find any
transient failure, like network, leader
change, etc. Okay? It will automatically
retry three times.
And the maximum in-flight request is
five.
This configuration we can add.
So, see.
If we don't know the internals of
producer, like this configuration is
like mugging up. Why we are setting it?
We don't know.
But if we know the internal of producer
that there are five, six steps, and for
each step there are already default
setup. But if you have to play according
to your component need,
then
you have to deal with all of this.
Okay, because this brings reliability,
resilience.
Okay? Whether you want all or one, like
what you want? Like again, I'm saying
only you would be able to use
application.properties properly if you
know the internal working, otherwise
your application.properties would only
have this one, bootstrap server.
And you might be thinking it works fine
out of the box, but there are a lot of
default happen in the
back.
Okay?
Now, let's see the use case two. Use
case two also we will keep everything
same. All I have to show you the custom
serializer.
Okay?
So,
serializer, the key is still I am a
string, and the value custom. We will
write a custom serializer. Okay?
Partitioner, now this time let's say we
have to send without key, so that a
sticky partition should be used. Rest
all same like previous.
So, no change in controller. I've just
exposed new endpoint with no key, and it
will just invoke the service layer. No
change in the controller.
Auto wiring is done properly. Okay, the
Kafka template. But you might be
thinking that
Okay.
This will like since we are using this
default
its properties will come from dot
properties file.
Because for serialization phase,
partitioner phase, record accumulator
all the properties for the Kafka
template will be built from
application.properties. Correct? So
for serializer key and value
I have currently defined here itself.
Key is a string serializer
and the value is this. Now
com.eda.producer.
So I've created a new class order
summary serializer. So I've provided its
path. This is my new class order summary
serializer.
And if you remember from the previous
uh
I have told you that all serialization
need to implement this serializer
interface.
Once you implement this interface, you
have to provide the override of this
method. That's all.
So the topic and the order like order in
the senses your object. So it's here it
is just nothing but a T.
So if it is an order type, you have to
just use that here.
Now I am doing nothing special here.
>> [snorts]
>> All I have done is that my requirement
is that hide the sensitive field.
So
see order have so many information pojo
order ID, customer ID, product ID,
quantity, amount, status.
In the byte when the byte is converted
Okay, I don't want all these fields to
go.
So that's what I am doing that I am
creating a map.
So key value
Okay.
So summary.output order ID
whatever I have put like this is the
order ID. Summary.output product ID
from the order I take out the product
ID. That's all.
So, I'm creating a map. This information
I need to send.
Okay, to the broker.
Only these two, order ID, product ID.
That's all. I don't want to send
customer ID, amount, the status,
everything.
And after that, I just do
object mapper
\dot} write value as bytes. So, normal
Java.
We can convert an object to a byte like
this.
Okay. So, this is my custom serializer.
So, in application.properties, value
serializer, I just provided this my
custom serializer.
Only this change. Rest all
application.property, I kept the same.
Okay. Internally, if you remember from
the Kafka
producer.java class,
it has serializer phase, right? So, when
it invoke the serializer, it will invoke
this now.
For the value.
Because for the value, I have provided
this one.
And that's all. The everything rest is
same. Kafka template \dot} send, your
topic, and without key, right? We wanted
That's why I went So, the override
method which I'm using for the send is
doesn't have a key. So, topic
and the value. That's all.
And here I am handling the callback.
>> [snorts]
>> Done.
Now, the question might have comes to
you that, okay, what if my producer has
like so many like
you can say that a publisher,
some is publishing order, some is
publishing something else.
Okay.
So, like here in the
application.properties, if you have put
order,
means my value should always be
use this serializer only.
Can't we have more than one serializer?
For example, like I have a controller
class one, controller class two here.
Order summary controller.
So, we have order controller. Let's say
you have some other different
controller. Sales controller, something
something something.
So, we can't we have
application.properties only one. Either
you can have a serializer for order or
for sales. You can't have like comma
separated right here.
What to do
when you have more than one you can say
that need a serializer for the value.
Okay?
We can use at the rate bean.
Very very simple. The same thing like in
the at the rate configuration class
in at the rate configuration class I
have just added one more bean. So, here
if you see
in at the rate configuration class
I have added one more bean here, this
one.
So, I am creating a map of properties
first.
Kafka properties. build producer
properties. So, what it will do is from
application.properties
all the Kafka producer related
properties it will load it first.
Start with all the producer properties
from application.properties.
It will load it. Now, we will only
override value.
Okay?
So, props So, this is the props.put
producer config.value serializer class
config. So, this enum has so many uh if
you open this class enum class, you have
so many values. You can just select one
whichever config you want to override.
So, I want to override value serializer.
Okay? And what is the value I need to uh
for for this serializer? This class,
order summary serializer.class.
That's all. Okay? Now, we have just
created a default Kafka producer factory
and put this props here.
Okay? Because Kafka template, we have to
return this object, right? Kafka
template object. So, we have to create
right new Kafka template.
This. We have to provide
So, open this one.
New Kafka template, if you open this, it
need producer factory.
Okay? So, producer factory is nothing
but
interface and default factory producer
factory is not the implementation of it.
So, that's what I'm just doing.
So, this is an implementation of
producer factory.
So, in that one, I have provided this
property, props.
Where I have overridden this value and
just feed it here. Return.
Now,
this [snorts] bean we have to use.
Okay? Now, wherever you have to use, for
example, in
order service, order producer service, I
have to use a specific bean, this bean.
You can do auto wired.
Okay? And put a qualifier, custom
serializer Kafka template like I put
custom serializer Kafka template.
Okay? I have put it here.
And this one, custom serializer Kafka
template.
>> [snorts]
>> So, the Kafka So, now, whenever you
want,
okay? When you have more than one Kafka
template exist, you can use like this.
So, here, I have also Kafka template.
So, this will read the properties from
application.properties.
Okay?
And another I have is custom serializer
Kafka template, which I have provided
here.
It will read from the
application.properties. After that, it
has overridden some values.
The value serializer. And
this object is created.
I have just auto wired that object here.
Now send without key, I am using custom
serializer Kafka template.
>> [snorts]
>> Okay? And in application.properties you
can put some default one. Let's say
JSON. In application.properties I'm
putting JSON serializer.
Okay? The same thing if you see
in application.properties
I have put JSON serializer
and Kafka producer config I am using
custom serializer Kafka template where I
have overridden the value serializer
part.
Order summary. So, let me put a breaker
point on this
>> [snorts]
>> serializer part. So, I put a
I will start into the debugging mode.
Okay? So, control should reach here to
our custom serializer.
And let's see that send with no key.
So, we have to invoke this endpoint.
Okay? And what it will do is that it is
using our custom serializer.
Yes, it is using our custom serializer.
dot send
Cool.
So,
let me start in a debug mode.
Now, let's hit the endpoint with
\hyphen} no \hyphen} key.
With \hyphen} no \hyphen} key, let's say
order ID is something O
\hyphen}
let's say
1 1 1 1.
Okay?
Product ID is PID 3, let's say.
And something something. Now, let's hit
it.
See, the control comes to our
serializer.
Custom serializer. From where it has
come?
Kafka producer.
Value serializer. \dot} serialize.
Okay? Instead of JSON serializer, it has
invoked our
Why? Because
it has used our
It has used uh
See, our Kafka template here. Custom
serializer Kafka template.
And in that configuration, we have
overridden the value serializer.
Okay?
Just finish it up.
See the console. Order events
successful. Partition two, offset zero.
Partition two. Who is the leader? Four.
Four is uh leader matlab broker two.
Controller one is ID one. Controller two
is ID two. Uh broker one is ID three.
And broker two is ID four.
So, partition two leader is broker two.
This is our broker two now. We are
inside broker two logs.
It is written inside partition two.
So, this is order event. Partition two
is like this one. \hyphen} two.
We need to check its log \dot} log.
So, it looks empty, but generally it
not. Like it's uh hide it generally. So,
generally what I do is control A, uh
control C. If I paste it somewhere
See,
it has certain data, but somehow it uh
hide it.
So,
order ID is 01111. That's what we have
given, right?
01111. Customer and we are just
uh putting product ID. That's all. We
are not adding customer ID, quantity, or
everything. Product ID PID 3. That's
all. Rest is all null null null.
So, data is going into the logs
properly.
Okay?
Now, only last part is in the producer
is, if you remember from the previous,
I told you there is a chance of
reordering, message reordering, when we
set this to config max in-flight request
per connection greater than one. Yes, we
have already set five greater than one.
Retry is also greater than zero. Yes.
Then, there is chance of message
reordering. How to solve this?
I will show you in the next part.
Any doubt, let me know. We can discuss
into the comment section. Bye.